

Felipe Quaglia Gambini

Brazilian Senior Data Analyst with 4 years of experience in the financial sector. As a focal point in board projects, I contribute strategic insights and actively participate in discussions with directors and stakeholders.

I value team collaboration and clear communication, with the aim of transforming data into information that drives growth and assertive decisions.

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Experience with data extraction, treatment, manipulation and visualization;
- Solid knowledge in Power BI, DAX, Python and SQL;
- Effective communication for committee presentations and interactions with stakeholders;
- Logical reasoning and analytical profile;
- Knowledge in financial products;
- Relationship with directors and investment fund;
- Experience in process automation;
- Participation in internal discussions, focusing on the search for insight through data;
- Focal point of the Board's projects;
- Participation in internal discussions, focusing on the search for insight through data;
- Business vision.

LANGUAGES

Native Portuguese

Advanced English

CONTACT

<u>(44) 99131-5400</u>

felipequagliagambini@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/felipegambini

felipegambini.github.io/curriculo

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Crefaz

Senior Data Analyst

Jan 2024 - Present

Focal point in high-level projects directly to the board, contributing with risk and financial analysis. Specialized in Python, pandas and SQL, performing complex analysis for the legal, controllership, finance and compliance sectors. Proactive in identifying bottlenecks and improvements, developing dashboards and automations that drive efficiency and strategic decision-making. Business vision and impact of decisions as a whole. Contact with the investment fund, helping in the audit of assignment, PDD and portfolio calculations.

Mid-Level Data Analyst

Jan 2023 – Dec 2024 (1 year and 1 month)

Development of the loss methodology based on the detailed analysis of the portfolio indicators, portfolio projection and monthly net profitability of the investment fund. Improvement of processes and analysis in the business intelligence team. Reference in Power BI and DAX, being consulted by colleagues for guidance. Construction of the visualization of the company's financial cash flow, standing out in presentations and delivering results directly to the board.

Junior Data Analyst

Feb 2021 – Dec 2022 (1 year and 11 months)

Assistance to a team of more than 100 supervisors, leading the route management project. Construction of analyses and dashboards using Power BI and DAX, standing out for proactivity and the development of skills in Python. Presentations to the board, contributing with strategic insights on financial and performance indicators. Beginning of learning about financial indicators such as loss, FPD, Recovery of 1st installment, Over, PDD and other portfolio indicators.

Data Assistant

Oct 2020 – Jan 2021 (4 months)

Responsible for building dashboards and automations for the sales team, using Power BI, Excel and VBA. Highlight in the automation of spreadsheets for bonus campaigns, providing valuable insights and KPIs. Knowledge about financial products and improvement of technical skills in data visualization.

State Revenue Service of Parana

Intern

May 2019 - Sep 2021 (4 months)

Internship at the State Revenue Service of Parana, an agency responsible for collecting and overseeing state taxes, as well as providing tax consulting and making decisions on administrative tax disputes, during graduation in Administration, first contact with the corporate environment. Development of essential skills such as communication and customer service; data management and process automation.

EDUCATION

State University of Maringa

Administration

2018 - 2024